Contact

brianj.galli@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/brian-galliphd-pe-pmp-lss-master-black-beltb893417 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Engineering Management Six Sigma Healthcare

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

Professional Engineer License in Industrial Engineering

Improvement Advisor Professional Development Program

Lean Six Sigma Blackbelt Certification

Lean Bronze Certified

Telephonics Corporation Greenbelt Certification in Six Sigma

Publications

Using Six Sigma to Improve Patient Safety in the Perioperative Process

Do Ethical Leaders Exist? A Unified Theoretical Framework to Identify and Evaluate Them

Brian Galli, PhD, PE, PMP, LSS Master Black Belt

Assistant Professor at Hofstra University Greenlawn

Summary

Over 5 years experience teaching and performing research in undergraduate and graduate programs in the fields of Engineering Management, Industrial Engineering and Management Engineering. Research in the fields of Lean, Six Sigma, Project Management, Healthcare, Organizational Development, Leadership Development, Team Dynamics and Team Development, Team Decision-Making, Operations Research/Management Science, and Innovation.

Over 8 years of experience in Lean Six Sigma in the manufacturing, healthcare, healthcare insurance, healthcare measure reporting, and academic environments. Proven to be an effective leader in fast-paced and project driven environments, with a strong record of successful results and accomplishments in these environments.

Skilled trainer, facilitator, speaker, author, and consultant in the areas of Lean, Six Sigma, Project Management, Management Engineering/Engineering Management, Industrial Engineering, and Continuous Improvement Methodologies. Hold several degrees, licensing, and certifications in Engineering Management, Industrial Engineering as well as Lean Six Sigma.

Experience

Hofstra University
Assistant Professor
September 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)
Long Island, NY

Provides instruction in the undergraduate Industrial Engineering program and the graduate Engineering Management program in the Fred DeMatteis School of Engineering and Applied Science at Hofstra University.

Perform research in the fields of Lean, Six Sigma, Project Management, Healthcare, Organizational Development, Leadership Development, Team Dynamics and Team Development, Team Decision-Making, Operations Research/Management Science, and Innovation.

International Journal of Productivity Management & Assessment Technologies

Co Editor in Chief

February 2018 - Present (2 years 10 months)

https://www.igi-global.com/journal/international-journal-productivity-management-assessment/45937

Long Island University - Post Campus 5 years 1 month

Assistant Professor of Computer Science & Management Engineering September 2015 - August 2019 (4 years)

Long Island University - Post Campus

Provides instruction in the undergraduate Computer Science programs and the graduate Management Engineering programs in the School of Computer Science, Innovation, and Management Engineering in the College of Management at Long Island University - Post Campus.

Perform research in the fields of Lean, Six Sigma, Project Management, Healthcare, Organizational Development, Leadership Development, Team Dynamics and Team Development, Team Decision-Making, Operations Research/Management Science, and Innovation.

Adjunct Instructor August 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 1 month) Brookville, New York

Provide instruction in the graduate Management Engineering program in topics such as Human Resource Management, Operations Research, Project/ Program Management, Operations Management, and Quality Management/ Quality Improvement.

American Public University System
Online Adjunct Instructor
September 2011 - August 2019 (8 years)
Remote/Online.

Provides online instruction in courses related to the field of Transportation and Logistics Management.

New York Institute of Technology Adjunct Instructor August 2010 - August 2019 (9 years 1 month)

Instructor in the Mechanical Engineering department. Provides instruction in several Industrial Engineering related courses including: Statistics, Project Management, Operations Management, Engineering Economy, Operations Research, Systems Simulation, Engineering Economics, and Technology and Global Issues (ethics course).

EmblemHealth
Manager, Quality Measurement
December 2014 - August 2015 (9 months)
Melville, New York

I lead a team that focuses on the reporting and quality improvement initatives around HEDIS/QARR reporting and additional key healthcare measures. I apply several Lean and Six Sigma tools in order to improve operational performance for services and processes within clinical and non-clinical operations as well as measures related to healthcare performance. I also provide hands on training on the tools of improvement such as Lean, PDSA, Six Sigma, and Project Management.

North Shore-LIJ Health System
Six Sigma Black Belt / Industrial Engineer
September 2011 - December 2014 (3 years 4 months)
Lake Success, New York

- •Responsible for supporting and driving the Six Sigma, Lean, and continuous improvement initiatives throughout the health system.
- •Develop and/or maintain the Six Sigma and Lean training curriculum; deliver the Six Sigma and Lean training curriculum to Six Sigma and Lean teams throughout the health system.
- •Mentor and lead Six Sigma, Lean, and continuous improvement projects throughout all areas and levels of the health system in order to monitor the progress of each team through each improvement methodologies; coordinate and perform pre and post project preparation for each Six Sigma and Lean project.
- •Prepare report out presentations and documentation for senior leadership and project sponsors; present project findings and results to project leadership and stakeholders at each project milestone.
- •For any improvement project:

- o Observe current operations and processes and gains understanding of all elements influencing work flow.
- o Determine best utilization of resources to attain desired outcomes.
- o Develop work and process flows to eliminate or mitigate blockages or slowdowns in existing processes.
- o Redesign processes to maximize efficiency and productivity.
- o Establishes methodologies and metrics to monitor trends and identify potential problems.
- o Recommend alternative methodologies to existing practices that maximize efficiency and are cost effective.
- o Develops and oversees implementation of process improvement programs.
- •Provide instruction at the Center for Learning and Innovation (CLI) in the following areas: Change Acceleration Management, Six Sigma, Lean, Microsystem, Model For Improvement (MFI), Fast-Track Decision-Making (FTD).
- •Provide facilitation and mentorship for activities and events throughout the health system that are lead by the Center for Learning and Innovation.

Stony Brook University
Adjunct Instructor
January 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 5 months)

Provided instruction in the graduate Engineering Management program in the area of Project and Program Management.

Telephonics Corporation
Reliability Engineer II/Industrial Engineeer
July 2007 - September 2011 (4 years 3 months)
Huntington, New York

Managed industrial engineering, reliability engineering and Lean Six Sigma initiatives throughout the organization. Developed continuous improvement and lean training curriculum; delivered training curriculum across the organization, to all levels of the organization. Managed and facilitated lean improvement projects and point-to-point kaizen improvement projects throughout all functions and levels of the organization; performed pre and post preparation for each lean improvement project.

Oversaw and supported lean improvement and point-to-point kaizen improvement project teams in order to monitor the progress and development of the improvement solutions. Monitored the progress of the improvement initiatives and projects (even post-project) through the use of performance

metrics and key performance indicators (KPIs). Maintained records and presented status of lean and point-to-point improvement projects to senior management as well as members of the improvement teams; based on performance of projects or initiatives, identified areas of improvement or training needs.

Developed program plans and implemented the reliability engineering program to comply with customer specifications by defining the product requirements with the assistance of various disciplines of engineering and operations. Ensured that corrective action measures meet acceptable reliability standards by collecting and analyzing program data and information; as necessary, proposed changes in design or formulation to improve system and/or process reliability. Prepared charts, calculations, graphs, and diagrams to illustrate recommended improvements to existing quality or production standards in order to achieve optimum quality. Determined the analytical approaches, the set of alternatives and evaluated findings and made recommendations among alternative solutions.

Education

Old Dominion University

Doctor of Philosophy, Engineering Management · (2009 - 2013)

Missouri University of Science and Technology

Masters of Science, Engineering Management · (2008 - 2009)

State University of New York at Binghamton
Bachelor's of Science, Industrial and Systems Engineering · (2003 - 2007)